RG 062:104, Town of Norwich
Connecticut State Library
Town of Norwich records
1729-1931, 1964
Connecticut State Library
Norwich (Conn.)
28 cubic feet
Administrative, school and tax records for the town of Norwich.
RG062_104
Multiple
Historical Note
The town of Norwich was settled in 1659, accepted as a legal township in May 1662. The city was incorporated in May 1784. The town and city consolidated on January 1, 1952.
Scope and Content
Administrative, school and tax records for the town of Norwich.
Index Terms
Subjects:
School enrollment -- Connecticut -- Norwich -- Statistics; Tax assessment -- Connecticut -- Norwich -- Registers; Taxation -- Connecticut -- Norwich -- Registers; Local taxation -- Connecticut -- Norwich -- Registers; Property tax -- Connecticut -- Norwich -- Registers
Places:
Norwich (Conn.) -- Records and correspondence
Restrictions on Access
Boxes 12-19 in accession T000311 are restricted due to condition. Accession T001928 is restricted. Please contact State Archives staff for assistance.
Box 2 in accession 2015-017 is restricted due to the Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act (FERPA) of 1974 which applies to all educational records including student records prior to the enactment of the law if the school or district was operating at or after enactment. This closure applies to the school registers after 1900 listed below as restricted.
Some of these records are stored at an off-site facility and therefore may not be available on a same-day basis.
See the policy.
Provenance
The records in accession 2015-017 were transferred to the Connecticut State Library by the Norwich Public Schools on October 21, 2014.
Container List
- Records, 1729-1900, 1964
  - T000311
    - First District School registers, 1839-1851 (Box Box 1)
    - Appraiser's rate book, 1799 (Box Box 1)
    - Town tax rate books, 1729-1794 (Box Box 1)
    - Highway tax rate book, 1818 (Box Box 1)
    - First Society rate books, 1730-1743 (Box Box 1)
    - Tax abstracts, 1752, 1754 (Box Box 1)
    - Tax abstracts, 1831-1900
      Tax abstracts for the years 1874 to 1900, other than those restricted, are not boxed. Boxes 11, 15-19 are on oversize shelving.
      Tax abstracts in boxes 12 to 19 are restricted due to condition.
      - 1831, 1832 (Box Box 2)
      - 1835, 1836 (Box Box 3)
      - 1839, 1840, 1841 (Box Box 4)
      - 1842,1845 (Box Box 5)
      - 1846, 1847 (Box Box 6)
      - 1850, 1851, 1852, 1853 (Box Box 7)
      - 1854, 1855, 1856, 1857 (Box Box 8)
      - 1858, 1859, 1860, 1861 (Box Box 9)
      - 1862, 1863, 1864, 1865 (Box Box 10)
      - 1866, 1867, 1868 (Box Box 11)
      - 1825, 1828, 1830, 1834 (Box Box 12)
        Restricted due to condition.
      - 1837, 1838, 1843, 1844 (Box Box 13)
      - 1848, 1849 (Box Box 14)
      - 1869 (Box Box 15)
      - 1870, 1871 (Box Box 16)
      - 1872, 1873 (Box Box 17)
      - 1878, 1895 (Box Box 18)
      - 1896, 1897 (Box Box 19)
      - 1874, 1 volume
      - 1875, 1 volume
      - 1876, 1 volume
      - 1877, 1 volume
      - 1879, 1 volume
      - 1880, 1 volume
      - 1881, 1 volume
      - 1882, 1 volume
      - 1883, 1 volume
      - 1884, 1 volume
      - 1885, 1 volume
      - 1886, 1 volume
      - 1887, 1 volume
      - 1888, 1 volume
      - 1889, 1 volume
      - 1890, 1 volume
      - 1891, 1 volume
      - 1892, 1 volume
      - 1893, 1 volume
      - 1894, 1 volume
      - 1898, 1 volume
      - 1899, 1 volume
      - 1900, 1 volume
  - T001928
    - Special Committee to Investigate Norwich Police Department records, 1964
      Restricted.
  - 2015-017, 4 cubic feet
    - School Records, 1855-1931
      - Connecticut St. Louis Exposition, 1904; 10 volumes (Box 1)
        On spine "Connecticut St. Louis Exposition Norwich", topic, and grade level from 4 to 9 or all grades. Topics covered by the volumes include: arithmetic, literature, author study, geography, language, United States history, and methode of teachers.
      - Register of Central School District, 1906-1907, 1911-1912; 2 volumes (Box 2)
        RESTRICTED
      - Connecticut Elementary School Register, 1930-1931; 1 volume (Box 2)
        Boswell Avenue School
      - Register of Central School District, 1855-1860 (Volume A)
        On front of volume: "Norwich Central School Society"
      - Register of Central School District, 1861-1865 (Volume B)
      - Register of Central School District, 1866-1869 (Volume C)
      - Register of Central School District, 1869-1873 (Volume D)
      - Register of Central School District, 1873-1877 (Volume E)
      - Register of Central School District, 1877-1881 (Volume F)
      - Register of Central School District, 1881-1884 (Volume G)
      - Register of Central School District, 1885-1889 (Volume H)
        Spine not embossed with letter "H"